Okay, it's high noon in Old Cheyenne.
Welcome to the February 18th Finance
Committee meeting. I'd like to call the
meeting to order. If you're in public,
please mute your cell phones. When
making public comment online, use the
raised hand function. in person.
Approach the podium. Remove your hat and
uh after the end of this agenda,
there'll be no additional business.
Remember, all communications go through
the chair. Clerk, please read the first
item.
>> Number 19 C, professional services
agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and TDSI for professional design
services for repurposing of the historic
pump house from general fund reserves.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair Jason Sanchez, Community Wreck
and Events. Uh before you and for your
consideration is a contract between the
city and TDSI for design of the historic
pump house. Um I want to give a little
bit of history on how we got to this
point. Um and and why I'm asking for
your support in this contract. Uh for a
number of years now, we've been trying
to find a location for our clean and
safe team. Our clean and stave team is
the group of employees or four full-time
employees that maintain our our downtown
infrastructure. Uh they they clean the
spiker garage, the Cox garage, they
maintain the 17th Street lot, the depot
plaza uh in the area surrounding um the
courthouse and some of the areas down
15th Street.
Currently, they have an office space on
the second floor of the Spiker garage.
And it's not necessarily an office
space. It's a storage area uh that we've
converted into an office space. It does
not have plumbing. Uh so they use they
have to go out and use public restrooms
when they need to use the facility. Um
we have their equipment spread out
behind some chain link fence on the
second floor of the spiker garage as
well as we store some of the trucks and
plows in the spiker garage. We also
store some of their trucks and trailers
at the city uh building parking lot, at
the accomplice parking lot, and at the
parking lot on 15th Street. So, for a
few years, I've been trying to find an
area in the downtown area that could
house their operations.
At one point, there was a building here
on O'Neal um that had some garage space
uh that we were interested in. However,
that is becoming it's turned into an
apartment complex uh which which is
great for the downtown. Um and so we we
understood that need and so we moved
away from that option. We also explored
an area right here by our fire station
on 19th Street, but again an adjacent
business um it would it would cause an
undue burden on them and so we moved
away from that.
With that said, over the years I've
listened to many u conversations at
council and in committee meetings and at
council goal setting regarding the pump
house. Uh there was a time when the city
entered into an agreement with TDSI to
do a design of the pump house to house
the chamber of commerce. And at that
time the city entered into an agreement
with TDSI to do the design for $439,539.
But at the end of 2025, after spending
$138,7220,
that contract was terminated because
there was no uh forward movement with
the potential tenant.
The council then looked at possibly
selling the property um and for a number
of months there was a solicitation for
people that might be interested in
purchasing the area and developing it.
But it's my understanding that we didn't
receive um interest in in that. And so
then there was the uh sunset date on
that that said in January if the
building hadn't sold or the property
hadn't sold that we would demo the
building. Um and then uh numerous people
came out and encouraged the council to
not demo the building. They they wanted
to find a different purpose for it or to
to salvage it. So hearing all of those
things, knowing that we had a need for
the clean and safe team, um I proposed
an idea of restoring the building and
making that the house of our clean and
safe uh division. Its proximity to
downtown is close enough that we can u
you know, we're not a long way away. We
could still address all of the downtown
maintenance needs that we uh that we're
tasked with. and it provides a space um
that is large enough to house all of the
equipment we have stored in multiple
areas around town. It also then gives us
an opportunity to preserve the building
and to fix the entire landscape of that
area. In this design, we would be uh
we'll build in uh plans for fencing off
the area. I'm hoping that we could do
something similar to what we did on the
south side of the depot uh building uh
the ornamental fence. Um, but that's how
we got to this point. Uh, the cost again
for this design is 198,93
and that's of the 300,000 remaining
dollars from the original contract. Some
of the work that TDSI had already
accomplished would be incorporated into
this plan with if we received your
support, we would have the design
completed by July. we'd go out to bid
for construction and then we'd be back
before the body with the cost of
construction and um see if we have your
support at that point as well. I do have
Randy Buyers with TDSI in attendance
with me and I'll stand by for any
questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee to the director?
>> Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Um so the 198,000
um would come out of the 300 that's
left. Is that correct? Or in addition to
>> Mr. Chair through you? It would be out
of the balance the $300,000 that was
originally allotted.
>> Councilman White, do you have any
comments or questions?
>> Uh just one uh question. Uh Mr. Chair,
thank you through you. Jason,
with the uh new agreement and I in
reading through it, is the uh is this
revised
um agreement going to contain something
uh with regard for access in and out of
uh the pump house? Should uh clean and
safe uh occupy that that property?
>> Mr. through you. Um in the first uh
phase of the design that TDSI uh
completed, um access was addressed and
so we would definitely be visiting that
again.
>> Okay, I'll go back and and reread that
because I to my knowledge I thought that
access was one of the things that was
left out of the original which uh kind
of always concerned me. But if I missed
that, I'll go back and reread that. So,
thank you. Thank you for that
information.
>> Okay, Councilman Wolf. Uh Mr. Chairman,
thank you very much. Uh through you, um
Director Sanchez, um thank you very much
for bringing this to us and for your
continued um uh involvement and interest
in this historic building. Um just a
little background for the the committee
and um uh uh Mr. Labour and Councilman
Labour and I met with uh Director
Sanchez yesterday morning uh and with
Megan and um Marin on behalf of historic
um preservation uh groups um and um we
um talked about um this proposed scope
of work um concerns some concerns that I
had uh with it. Um I yesterday I um
spent uh some time um reddrafting it and
um sent it to Mr. Director Sanchez last
night and um and he was able to get
together with Mr. Buyers and TDSI and
and um that's what we have uh before us
now is a revised uh scope of work which
I um I I think um is terrific. Um, and
it um uh really addresses some of the
key and related issues which are not
only the the building and the building
preservation, but also access as
Councilman White indicated, but um
landscaping, fencing, uh the things that
actually the general public sees and and
uh feels um feels very committed to for
and uh I just compliment the the
historic uh preservation groups that
have had they had an open house which
had more than 200 people at it. And so
there's a lot of interest in this.
There's a lot of um uh public awareness
about what's going on. And um Dr.
Sanchez, I just really applaud your
continued efforts to try and figure out
a way to uh help make this building a a
useful and and uh and reality for us.
Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you, director. Uh, we'll go to
public comment now.
>> Hello, my name is Megan Stanfill. I'm
the executive director of the Alliance
for Historic Wyoming. We are the
statewide nonprofit dedicated to
historic preservation and um we worked
with the historic preservation board and
Historic Cheyenne Inc. in hosting the
tour of the building back in November
and it was an overwhelming success. Um
I'm very very impressed with the current
proposal. I'm excited to hear that the
city would like to retain possession of
the building and retain it for public
benefit. I think that's that honors the
legacy of the building and it honors um
the the ability to
keep the community in that area um in
mind when when you're making decisions
about development and economic
development in that area. Um, I would
like to also say that we um
when when we hosted the tour, we asked a
question of of attendees. We asked them,
"Do you want to see the see the pump
house saved or do you want to see it
demolished?" And overwhelmingly, we had
127 people say yes. We had two people
say no. And I I I want to reiterate that
the the question there was keep the
building standing or not. Not what do
you want to see in it, not where do you
want to see this go. I I think that this
proposal here is a testament to saving
the building, using the building, and
keeping it um alive. So, thank you.
Good afternoon, finance committee. Marin
Callis, vice president historic braided.
I just um would like to uh offer my
support to this um very viable idea. Um
the pump house was part of streets and
alleys for much longer than it was
actually a water pumping facility. it
became um streets and alleys became a
steward of this building in the 20s and
I don't think vacated until early 90s
perhaps. So um this isn't even a a jump
from what it has been. It um I think
that parks taking over this space is um
perfect for where we're at right now.
And I know some of the commentary from
the walkthrough we had was, "Oh, a
brewery, a museum, you know, um a
concert venue." And those are all great
ideas. I just don't think we're there
right now. And um I think that the
solution coming from within the city and
u through the parks um is is great
because it it also addresses the
adjacent issues which is the land that
it sits on. um they will they are the
perfect branch of the city to have boots
on the ground for developing the land or
working with it or just making it
better. The greenway goes through there
or maybe the greenway will go through
there and uh it's it is part of the West
Edge idea, the grand plan. Maybe in five
decades that will come to fruition and
the building will still be standing. So
I don't think we have another decade to
wait. I don't think we have a hundred
years. I don't have, you know, we we
can't wait. This is it. This is this is
our chance. So, I I'm really in support
of it on behalf of um HCI. Thank you.
>> Any further public comment in the room?
How about online?
>> Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, uh I um move to uh
approve the um contract uh with uh the
city and um TDSI
uh in the amount of
what?
>> Not to exceed
>> not to exceed
I don't have that.
Oh, I I apologize. not to exceed uh
$198,93.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
seconded by Councilman White.
Any further discussion?
Further discussion on the main motion or
do you want to go move the substitute?
need a motion on the substitute.
>> Well, Mr. Chairman, I guess there's a a
question is whether this is really a
substitute.
It is it is
>> Mr. Chairman, it's a substitute because
the original document was posted with
the original contract. So, we are
subbing out that contract at that point.
>> All right. Well, Mr. Chairman, I would
move to adopt uh as a substitute. We're
not actually changing the language of
the contract itself, but we are changing
the scope of work that is uh an
attachment to the contract.
That document is dated February 18th,
2026.
>> Correct. Okay. Can I get a second?
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman
Wolf and seconded by Councilman White.
Uh any comments or on the substitute
from the committee?
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Dr. Evans.
>> Um I I just need some clarification. Um
so the dollar amount is the same as what
we had on the previous
um
>> that message.
>> Okay. So dollar amount hasn't changed,
but this is what's changed. the scope of
service. Is that correct? Can you um
give me just kind of a thumbnail of what
this the changes are in the scope?
>> Um certainly um Mr. Chairman uh through
you. Um Dr.
Um,
what I did is I was as I was reddrafting
this is to try and just bring some
additional clarity to this because of
the really strong public interest in
that. I I just felt that the the scope
of work ought to be able to be
understood by anybody who chose to come
look at it. So, one of the additions
that I asked um uh director Sanchez and
TDSI to make is to include the
photographs which I took uh on this
Monday of the building um and they've
done that um and labeled them um so that
anybody reading the document can can
look and see what is being kept, what is
being demolished and um and so you don't
have to go down to the building and
check yourself. Uh the second thing that
um I added to this um and that's been
adopted is um just a description of the
clean and safe program itself so that um
anybody reading this will understand
what what we're trying to do and why and
why this building is being turned into
both an office, a break room, a
restroom, and then storage for vehicles,
equipment, and tools. Um, and so that's
uh the the
main changes in the first couple
paragraphs of this. Um, next I wanted to
have a u a just a fuller discussion of
the prior work that TDSI has done on
this building. Um, so I think it's
important to recognize that the firm has
uh developed considerable expertise uh
as a result of uh prior contract um with
the city um and that um we benefit we
the city benefit from that uh expertise
and that they will apply it uh into this
contract and and end up saving us some
money. We believe um the next several
paragraphs are all basically from the
original draft of the scope of work with
some elaborations that I um I I thought
were necessary and some particularly
some orientations to the building
itself. Um the the um original draft uh
in paragraph what is now paragraph 8
talks about raising the floor and it
wasn't clear at all how much the floor
was going to be raised. This is
apparently done for um flood uh
protection reasons but it's going to be
raised about 18 in. Um this is the floor
under the main part of the um uh
existing building. Um and um the
paragraph nine is the discussion which
is um just sort of modified and edited
um that I I did to describe the main
work that's uh being done uh in the in
the building and the uh addition and
then um added three paragraphs um to
deal with access fencing and
landscaping. Um it's these are key
issues. Um and I wasn't um clear because
they weren't addressed in the original
draft how they were going to be affected
by this contract. And uh I thank
Director Sanchez and TDSI for looking at
that and responding to those uh
questions. And that's what you see
before you in uh the draft dated
February 18th. Those are the those are
the primary changes. Um Dr. Emmens.
>> Dr. Evans.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. So I maybe this
isn't even my thing to worry about, but
it's my day to worry apparently. So is
this does this pass our lawyers muster
as far as a contract or is this what
we're going to use to then develop the
contract?
Uh, Mr. Chairman, uh, committee, David
Hopinson, deputy city attorney. I don't
believe that that has been through our
offic's review. I'm not sure if John's
taken a look at it, but if not, I I
guess my preference would certainly be
perhaps that we could review it prior to
the council meeting and then it could be
brought up at the council meeting on
Monday. But I'm I guess I'm not sure if
um, John has taken a look at it or not,
but I know I haven't. Uh, Mr. Chairman,
through you if I might. Um, this this is
not I mean it's it's all happened within
the last 24 hours. Uh, and um and and
again the the actual contract which the
city attorney has reviewed is not being
changed. This is this is a little odd
because we're actually changing the
proposal
of the scope of work itself. Um and so
it obviously required TDSI to agree to
that and and um from the cover letter
they they have done that. So um but
certainly the um if uh uh I guess I
would recommend that we act on it today
and then we've got time uh over the next
week before the council meeting to uh to
have a city attorney review it. And um
it's as I said it's fundamentally what
they originally proposed with some
elaborations to it.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay, Dr. Evans.
>> Thank you. So I guess I just I I
don't have an issue with the intent by
any means. I just want to make sure that
we do it legally so that we don't end up
back here talking about the same thing
again. So, I guess as long as we know
this is still going to go back to the
lawyers for review and to put into
contractual form prior to the next um
council meeting.
I I'm okay with that. I just want to
make sure that we're doing this the
right way.
>> Um
>> Mr.
when we review the contracts generally
we also review the this obviously the
exhibits to that uh and so in in my mind
they would be part and parcel of one
whole uh so I I I do think best
practices would be to have our office
review if we're going to change the the
scope um you know the attachments to the
contract uh just to make sure that
there's not and I'm not certainly not
implying that there's anything wrong
with with what Councilman Wolf has
brought forward uh just, you know, as
always to be safe, our office certainly
prefers to take a look at those. Um, I
don't know that there would necessarily
be a legal issue, but I think a
practical issue uh would be would be
best to have our office take a look at
them.
>> Councilman White, do you have any
comments or questions on the substitute?
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chair. Um,
having read through this, I don't see I
certainly don't see anything wrong with
it. However, um
the the process that we've followed over
the time uh that I've been involved in
council would be to have uh finished
this document, send it to uh city
attorney's office for review, and then
uh have added it uh at at our uh full uh
meeting of the governing body next week
um so that we could uh get their
approval on this beforehand.
um to to do that without the review I
think would be a little bit inconsistent
uh to what we've done uh in the past.
Again, looking through this and I got
this at uh almost 9:00 last night. Um in
looking through it, I I see nothing
wrong with it. Um, I would just
personally prefer to uh have this
reviewed by the city attorney's office
and then um incorporate that into uh the
professional services agreement at the
meeting next week.
>> Okay. Um let's go to public comment on
the substitute.
Okay. Uh, ready to vote. All in favor of
the substitute,
please say I.
>> I post. No.
>> No.
>> The substitute is failed. We're back on
the main motion. Any further comments or
questions?
>> Get a vote. All in favor of the main
motion, please say I.
>> I.
The recommendation of the finance
committee will be to approve at the next
meeting of the governing body. Madam
clerk, next item.
>> 19D. Utility easement agreement between
the city corporation for grant of
perpetual perpetual rideaway and
temporary easement for underground fiber
lines revenue to the city.
>> Staff report.
>> Uh chair, members of the finance
committee, Jean Shrednick, parks and
greenway planner. Um, I'm bringing this
to you because it essentially goes
through our CB and Q land that uh the
city owns. Um, it's basically a uh an
easement for Microsoft to get some fiber
um to their site at the Bronco Philly
site. Um nothing unusual. Um
it uh came in with an appraised value um
that Microsoft did. Um the value is
$1,265
and that would be go towards the city.
Um I'd be happy to answer any questions.
Also, uh Brad Emmens with AVI is here uh
representing Microsoft if you have any
questions for him.
>> Comments or questions from the committee
to the staff. Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Is there a
downside to this
>> uh chair through you? Um um Councilwoman
Emmens, I don't believe so. We've given
a lot of easements along this corridor
um for different purposes. We always
make sure that the depths are right so
that if we do do a future greenway there
or something um that we won't it won't
affect the construction of those sorts
of things. Um, so I feel like it's it's
very it's very common to do this.
>> Councilman White, you got any comments
or questions for staff?
>> I do not, Mr. Chair.
>> We go to the public comment.
Mr. Evans,
>> chairman, council members, Brad Amens,
AVI agent for Microsoft on this. A
couple things I would point out for uh
councilman councilwoman Dr. Emmens. Um
we did uh align this at a 90 degree
exact at a 90 degree angle to limit the
amount of area that it's instead of
following along the corridor we kind of
came up and then crossed at a 90. So
that shrinks that easement corridor uh
to about the smallest amount it could
be. Um also running through there is a
sewer line uh fiber optic lines from the
two BOPU corridor. So this is really a
fiber corridor already. So it's not
really uh you know getting any more
easements in the area. It's actually
going over areas that other have
easements. Um I would want to point out
one thing that I would like the council
to consider in the future. Um in a
situation like this um the appraisal was
actually more expensive than the
easement. I I think that on the staff or
the council should come up with a if the
easement is so small and it it's not
affecting something that there could be
a flat fee that could be paid um to get
for these types of easements. Um it
seemed silly to wait three or four weeks
for an appraisal that costs three times
as much as the value of these things.
So, I don't know if that's a direction
to give staff or something to do maybe
do a little study on ways that we could
get these done a little bit quicker
through the through the process. So,
just a little tidbit for as you're
moving forward on things. Be happy to
answer any other questions.
Any questions for Mr. Edmonds?
Any further public comment?
Any comments online?
See, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve in the
amount of $10. Is that right?
>> Yes.
>> Second. It's been moved by Dr. Edmonds,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Any further
comments or discussions?
Ready to vote. All in favor signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> Opposed?
Seeing none, the recommendation of the
finance committee will be to approve at
the next meeting of the governing body.
Next item,
>> number 20 C, contract modification
number three to contract number 7977
between the city of Cheyenne and Simon
Contractors for the public works
improvements project from the 2019 to
2022 optional 1% sales tax fund, fleet
maintenance fund, and solid waste fund.
>> Staff report.
Adele Adele Bartell, public works staff
engineer. Um, for this contract
modification, we are requesting
$266,4649
for Simon contractors to um complete
some additional concrete repairs due to
concrete failure in areas over the last
three years since the beginning of this
project.
I'll be happy to take any of your
questions. Any comments or questions
from the committee to staff? Dr. Evans,
>> do we know why the contra or the
concrete has failed?
>> Uh, Mr. Chair, through you. Um, it's
just very old concrete and it was in
good condition when we started the
project and as of now it's starting to
crumble. Um, an example would be like
the sidewalk over here to the building
has some um, slabs that are cracking all
the way through. Um there's others that
are that might pose a hazard.
>> Any further comments or questions from
the committee to staff?
We'll go out to public comment.
See none in the room. Any public comment
online?
Seeing none online. Can I get a motion?
>> Um Mr. Chairman, I uh move to accept the
bid in amount not to exceed $266,4649.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
seconded by Councilman White. Any
further comments or discussions?
Seeing none, ready for a vote. All in
favor say I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed?
>> Seeing none opposed. The met
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item
>> number 20D contract modification number
one to contract number 7821 between the
city of Sh and United Way of Larry
County to provide funding to community
agencies and monitor performance for
community pro programs from the 2019 to
2022 optional 1% sales tax fund.
>> Staff report
your microphone. Ma'am,
your microphone needs Thank you.
>> better now.
>> Yes.
>> Okay, Mr. Chair. Um,
this is just a contract mod to our
existing uh contract 7821 with United
Way. Um, we're replacing the old exhibit
with a new exhibit which basically
revises the allocation of the funding um
to the nonprofit organizations and some
changes to the indiv individual funding
amounts. Um, but we're still maintaining
the same overall contract amount of
250,000. So there's no changes to the
actual um
the the city's funding to United Way.
Any comments or questions from the
committee to staff?
Any public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve.
>> Second.
It's been moved by Dr. Edmonds, seconded
by Councilman White. Any further
comments or discussions?
Ready for vote. All in favor say I.
>> I.
>> Post. No.
Seeing none, the recommendation of the
finance committee will be to approve at
the next meeting of the governing body.
Next item, please.
>> Number 21D. consideration of bid number
S-9-26
for an agreement between the city of and
Aztec Construction Company Incorporated
for the Kowanas Park Trail and
Constructed Wetlands Project from the
2017 specific purpose tax fund and
Wyoming Department of Environmental
Quality Grant.
>> Staff report
>> uh chair through you Jean Shrednik Parks
and Greenway Planner. Um, we are finally
getting to the point where we have bid
out our Kanis project, our Quanis Park
project. We've been working on this for
a long time. Um, trying to get DEQ
grants and get designs done. And so, um,
we recently put out put it out to bid.
Um, Aztec Construction um was the lowest
bid at $487,650.
Um, just wanted to remind you that this
project is has been um a project that's
very uh uh the community-minded.
Um, we received $80,000 from the Kuanas
Club for this project. We received $2500
from our uh High Plains Ottabon Society.
We've received $3,000 from our Greenway
um foundation, $800 from our women's
civic league, um $1,000 from our the
conservation district, and then the rest
of the um we would be using funds from
our six penny. Um I'd be happy to answer
any questions for you.
>> Comments or questions from the committee
to staff
lights on?
U Mr. Rnik, uh I did have a question.
Will there be some interpretive signing
there for um people that are using those
trails about dogs being kept on leash?
>> Um we do have um educational signage
that we're going to put up along the
trails. Um those are specific to
riparian areas and native wildlife and
that kind of thing. Um, I think that we
might really have to do something more
about the trash pickup and the dog
things that are going out there. But my
hope is that by building these new um
wetlands and trails that we get more use
and maybe um sometimes we hope for other
users to say, "Hey, you know, please
keep your dog on leash." But it's it has
been a battle.
>> Hey, thank you. Uh, can you explain
further about the bird vines? What with
those?
>> Um, I'd be happy to send you um pictures
of those, but um they are currently
being fabricated. They'll be two uh C10
steel bird blinds um with a really kind
of an a very nice design. Um, we walked
out there several years ago with the
Cheyenne Ottabon Society and pick the
locations for those blinds so that folks
could go out there and quietly view um
all the wildlife, especially the birds.
Um, Otabon Society found 52 species of
birds at the existing wetlands pond out
there.
>> Thank you. Mike, that's why my name
first comment was dogs and birds don't
mix real well. I agree.
I agree. And we have um since we
purchased the park and opened it to the
public, we have been doing a closure on
at least that southern end of the park.
Um not too confident that dogs aren't
running through the fences and the
gates, but hopefully it helps. Um, we
have, um, the closure signs all along
that fence, um, to hopefully keep people
from sending their dogs in there and
harassing wild wildlife. Um, it's just
it's a nesting season, so we close it
um, uh gosh, April 1st to July 15th.
Uh, any further comments or questions
from the committee to staff? Any
public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Seeing none. Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, um I move to accept the
bid in the amount not to exceed 487,656.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
seconded by Dr. Emmens. Any further
comments or questions?
Seeing none, we're ready to vote. All in
favor say I.
>> I.
>> Opposed? No.
And that's uh unanimous. Uh the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item,
please.
>> 21E. Consideration of bid number E-8-26
for furnishing one new 52K GVWR
truck with trash loader and dump body
for the forestry division from one-time
state distribution funds
>> staff report. Mr. Chair, Jason Sanchez,
community wreck and events. Uh before
you and for your consideration is for a
bid for a grapple truck for our city
forestry division. Um, our forestry uh
division uses this on emergency call
outs to clear fallen trees and large
branches from the streets and sidewalks
when we have inclement weather. Last
year they had approximately 30 emergency
callouts where this vehicle was
utilized. We also use it for large tree
removals um because this truck and this
grapple can haul 15 and 16 foot logs.
Last year we did 258 large tree
removals. Without this unit, moving
large logs becomes very difficult and
dangerous. Uh, we also use it for
picking up and hauling stump grindings
and picking up brush piles from around
the city. The current unit we have is a
2010 truck, but the grapple unit is an
early 2000s model, which does not have
many of the safety features that the new
model does. Um, I would stand by for
questions, but my request is for your
support in approving the bid from
Floyd's Truck Center in the amount of
$253,260.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee to staff?
>> Uh, Mr. Chair, just one comment. Um,
Jason,
just wanted to uh thank you for
including the information on the
five-year extended warranties on engine
and after treatment system and the
transmission. Um, over the years I've
often asked department directors when
they come to us with uh requests for new
vehicle purchases kind of what kind of
what kind of warranties are included in
those just so I know that we're getting
the best bang for our buck and I
appreciate you including that in this.
Let's go to public comment in the room.
Any public comment online?
And I get a motion.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
from Floyd's Truck Center Incorporated
in an amount not to exceed $253,260.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Dr. Emman, seconded
by Councilman White. Any further
comments or questions?
Seeing none, can I get a vote? All in
favor say I.
>> I.
No.
See, and there's it's unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item,
please. Number 21F, consideration of bid
number E-12-26
for furnishing one new recycle and
high-pressure water jet truck 66K
GVWR
for the street and alley division from
the 2019 to 2022 optional 1% sales tax
fund
>> staff report. Good afternoon chairman
and committee members Craig Laoy works.
This is for our street and alley
division. When we use this recycling
vacuum, high-pressure water jet to do
all the storm sewers and we also use it
when there's emergency fuel spills. Um,
we have over 200 inlets. Um, I'm excited
that we're finally going to get this.
This is really going to help us in a lot
of ways and do our job more efficiently
and faster and hopefully better. And I
recommend approval with Kaiser Premiere
for $848,639.
And I stand for any questions.
Dr. Evans.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Do we have one of
these now that we're replacing or is
this a first time
>> through you, Chair? We have one existing
that we bought used
probably before I got here and I've been
here 16 years. So, we are replacing
this. Yes.
>> Any further comments or questions for
staff? Councilman Wolf.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. through you. What
exactly does this machine do?
Through you, chair. It It is think of it
as a wet vac. I mean, it you can
pressure water down through to break up
debris that's in the storm waters and
then it sucks it back out, the leaves,
trash, litter, whatever else has fallen
in there. Um, it'll actually even help
us with the the famous gutter bins down
there to help try to suck those out a
little bit easier. it it'll lift bins
out so we can dump them. Um, so that's
kind of what it does. It kind of has a
biddility to pressure wash down through
the storm drain and then suck the debris
back up that's there.
>> Mr. Chairman, a followup.
>> Yeah.
>> So, is this used on a I mean on a
scheduled basis? So, you're routinely
uh using this uh on the city's systems
or is it mostly when you have identified
problems that need to be fixed
immediately? Uh through you, chair, we
have schedules in the spring and the
fall, we try to hit everyone in town.
And then, of course, if there's
something that's, you know, big storm
event or something we had to go down and
plug, we would take this down there and
we would tackle that one item at a time.
But we do hit almost every try to hit
every one every year.
>> Uh followup, Mr. Chair, through you. Um
is this a very expensive vehicle? Is
this is this one that the fleet
maintenance shop can in fact uh maintain
and repair?
>> You chair? Uh yes, it is. And of course,
you know, when it's warranty and
specific issues with the back part, it
would be somewhat similar to firet
trucks. You'd sometimes have to send it
back to the manufacturer, but we should
be able to handle most repairs.
Any further questions for staff from the
committee?
Go to public comment.
Anything online?
see the none. Can I get a motion?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, um I move to accept uh
Kaiser Premiere
uh bid in the amount not to exceed
$848,639.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman White. Any further
comments or discussion?
>> Seeing none, ready to vote. All in favor
say I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed? Seeing none, the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Seeing there's no
more business before the finance
committee, we are ajourned.